Hello everyone and welcome to EnglishPod.
大家好，欢迎收听EnglishPod。
My name is Marco.
我是Marco。
My name is Catherine and today we've got a very special lesson for you all about time.
我是Catherine，今天我们为大家准备了一节非常特别的课程，全部关于时间。
That's right.
没错。
We're going to concentrate a little bit on some specific points of grammar this time
这次我们会重点讲一些具体的语法点。
and we're going to talk about the morning routine, what you do in the mornings.
我们会讨论早晨的例行事务，也就是你早上做的事情。
Well, let's take a look first at the word routine.
好，我们先来看看“routine”这个词。
This is our vocabulary preview for today.
这是今天的词汇预览。
Vocabulary preview.
词汇预览。
Alright so a routine or the morning routine.
好的，所以“routine”或“morning routine”。
What is a routine?
什么是“routine”？
A routine is basically your habit for a certain period of time.
“routine”基本上就是你在某段时间内的习惯。
So for example, your routine in the morning is what you do when you wake up.
比如，你早上的例行事务就是你醒来后做的事情。
Get breakfast and go to work.
吃早餐然后去上班。
You can also have an evening routine.
你也可以有晚上的例行事务。
It's what you always do before you go to bed.
就是你睡觉前总是做的事情。
Exactly.
没错。
Everyone has a routine, what they do in the mornings, maybe what you do at night before
每个人都有例行事务，他们早上做什么，也许你晚上睡觉前做什么。
going to bed.
睡觉前。
So that's what we're going to talk about today.
这就是我们今天要讨论的内容。
That's right.
没错。
You can also have an exercise routine.
你也可以有锻炼的例行事务。
So basically anything with steps.
所以基本上任何有步骤的事情。
One, two, three, four, five, that you always do the same way.
一、二、三、四、五，你总是以同样的方式做。
That's a routine.
那就是例行事务。
Exactly.
没错。
Right.
对。
So that's what we're going to take a look at today.
所以这就是我们今天要看的。
Let's actually jump right into our dialogue and listen to Stephanie's routine.
让我们直接进入对话，听听Stephanie的例行事务。
Stephanie did you just get to school?
Stephanie，你刚到学校吗？
But you were up and about when I left the dorm this morning.
但我早上离开宿舍的时候你已经起床活动了。
That was about an hour and a half ago.
那大约是一个半小时前。
This happens all the time.
这种事经常发生。
Why do you always take so long to get ready in the mornings?
为什么你早上总是花那么长时间准备？
It's a skill.
这是一种技能。
What can I say?
我能说什么呢？
I don't know why.
我不知道为什么。
I just have a long routine.
我只是有一个很长的例行事务。
Please explain because it makes no sense to me.
请解释一下，因为我觉得这完全说不通。
How can a girl's routine be so complicated?
一个女生的例行事务怎么能这么复杂？
You get up, you shower, you get dressed, you brush your teeth, you're out the door.
你起床、洗澡、穿衣服、刷牙，然后出门。
Half an hour tops.
最多半小时。
Jacob, you have the luxury of having a haircut that rarely needs styling.
Jacob，你幸运地有一个几乎不需要造型的发型。
I don't.
我没有。
I have to set aside about an hour and a half to get ready in the mornings.
我早上必须留出大约一个半小时来准备。
Every day I wake up and head straight for the shower.
每天我醒来就直接去洗澡。
Every second day I wash my hair.
我每隔一天洗一次头发。
If it's a hair washing day, I frequently need to wash my hair twice because it gets really
如果是洗头日，我经常需要洗两次头发，因为它会变得很油。
oily.
很油。
Then, I usually put in a conditioner and have to rinse that out too.
然后，我通常会涂护发素，还得把它冲洗掉。
Because my hair is so long, I seldom manage to take a shower in under 20 minutes.
因为我的头发很长，我很少能在20分钟内洗完澡。
Afterwards, I often put on a pot of coffee and get dressed while I wait for it to brew.
之后，我经常煮一壶咖啡，在等它煮好的时候穿衣服。
I take a long time to get dressed in the morning.
我早上穿衣服要花很长时间。
Every now and then I remember to choose my outfit the night before, but usually I do
偶尔我会记得前一天晚上选好衣服，但通常我都是早上才选。
it in the morning.
早上才选。
In all, getting dressed takes about half an hour, at which time my hair is now semi-dry
总的来说，穿衣服大约需要半小时，这时我的头发半干了。
so then I have to style my hair.
所以然后我得打理头发。
From time to time I'll put my hair up, but oftentimes I blow dry it straight.
有时候我会把头发扎起来，但通常我会用吹风机吹直。
And then, because of the texture of my hair, I regularly have to flat iron it to keep it
然后，因为我的发质，我经常需要用直发夹板来防止它毛躁。
from frizzing.
防止它毛躁。
That's another 20 minutes or so.
那又是大约20分钟。
After that, I have my daily makeup routine.
之后，我进行每天的化妆流程。
True, I hardly ever see you without your hair done and your makeup on, even when you show
确实，我几乎从没见过你不弄头发、不化妆的样子，即使你穿着运动裤来上课。
up to class in sweatpants.
穿着运动裤来上课。
Tell me, how long does it take you to choose that outfit in the morning?
告诉我，你早上选那套衣服要花多长时间？
Not funny.
不好笑。
Alright, we're back.
好了，我们回来了。
So obviously she has a very complicated routine.
所以很明显她有一个非常复杂的例行事务。
I don't know if all girls are like this.
我不知道是不是所有女生都这样。
I'm not like this, but I think a lot of girls, and some guys are.
我不是这样，但我认为很多女生，还有一些男生是这样。
I don't want to be sexist here.
我不想在这里有性别歧视。
I know some guys who take their time in the morning and are very, very particular about
我知道有些男生早上会慢慢来，而且非常非常在意自己的外表。
the way that they look.
自己的外表。
Really?
真的吗？
Wow.
哇。
So, obviously everyone has their morning routine in different ways.
所以，显然每个人都有自己不同的早晨例行事务。
And it was interesting to see how she described it.
看她怎么描述这件事很有趣。
So why don't we take a look at Language Takeaway.
所以我们来看看“语言要点”部分。
Language Takeaway.
语言要点。
So today's Language Takeaway, like I said at the beginning of the podcast, is all about
所以今天的语言要点，就像我在播客开头说的，全是关于
time.
时间。
So we're going to look at some of these important time adverbs.
所以我们要看一些重要的时间副词。
That's right.
没错。
These are called adverbs of frequency.
这些被称为频率副词。
And basically, they are telling us how we do things.
基本上，它们告诉我们做事情的方式。
If we do something all the time or if we never do something.
如果我们一直做某事，或者从不做某事。
Or everything in between.
或者介于两者之间的一切。
Exactly.
正是。
So the first couple we have today are very, very common words.
所以今天的前几个词是非常非常常见的词。
You're going to hear these a lot.
你会经常听到它们。
The first one is frequently.
第一个是“frequently”。
Okay, frequently.
好的，“frequently”。
So, if you do something frequently, consider it to be about 75% of the time.
所以，如果你经常做某事，可以认为大约75%的时间。
Maybe a little bit more, almost 85% of the time.
可能多一点，几乎85%的时间。
Right.
对。
So it's not always, but it's very often.
所以不是总是，但非常频繁。
So for example, so I frequently forget to take my keys when I'm leaving the house, which
例如，我经常在离开家时忘记带钥匙，这
is a very big problem.
是个大问题。
Exactly.
正是。
So considering out of seven days, maybe you forget your keys five days.
所以考虑到七天里，你可能五天忘记钥匙。
Not so good.
不太好。
All right.
好的。
So that's frequently.
这就是“frequently”。
Now let's move on to another one that's actually a lot less.
现在来看另一个频率低得多的词。
We talk about seldom.
我们谈谈“seldom”。
Well, Marco has told me that he seldom forgets his keys.
嗯，Marco告诉我他很少忘记钥匙。
That means he almost always remembers them.
这意味着他几乎总是记得。
Right.
对。
So seldom is a negative adverb.
所以“seldom”是一个否定副词。
It's saying that almost never.
它表示几乎从不。
Okay.
好的。
So if I say, for example, I seldom go to the movies.
所以如果我说，例如，我很少去看电影。
That's too bad.
那太可惜了。
I like the movies.
我喜欢电影。
Right.
对。
Well, that means that I maybe go to the movie theater once a month.
嗯，那意味着我可能一个月去一次电影院。
Yeah.
是的。
Not very often.
不经常。
Seldom.
很少。
Not very often.
不经常。
Seldom.
很少。
All right.
好的。
Now going back to a positive adverb of frequency, we have often.
现在回到一个肯定的频率副词，我们有“often”。
You described frequently as very often.
你把“frequently”描述为非常频繁。
That's right.
没错。
You can also say, I often forget my keys or it often rains in tropical places.
你也可以说，我经常忘记钥匙，或者热带地区经常下雨。
This means this is a common thing.
这意味着这是常见的事情。
Exactly.
正是。
So again, let's consider it to be about 70 to 80% of the time.
所以再次，我们把它看作大约70%到80%的时间。
Now with pronunciation, some people like to pronounce often, right?
关于发音，有些人喜欢读成“often”，对吧？
They kind of leave out the strong T sound.
他们有点省略了强T音。
Well, other people say often.
嗯，其他人说“often”。
That's right.
没错。
Both forms are correct, right?
两种形式都正确，对吧？
Yes, they're both correct.
是的，它们都正确。
So you're safe using either of these.
所以用任何一种都没问题。
Right.
对。
Okay.
好的。
And our third adverb of frequency, no, our fourth.
我们的第三个频率副词，不，是第四个。
And our fourth adverb of frequency is also a positive one and we say usually.
我们的第四个频率副词也是一个肯定的，我们说“usually”。
Usually means this is something that you do pretty consistently.
“Usually”意味着你相当一致地做某事。
I usually brush my hair before I go to sleep.
我通常在睡觉前梳头。
That means not always, but almost every day.
这意味着不是总是，但几乎每天。
Right.
对。
So let's consider out of seven days, you do it six times.
所以考虑七天里，你做六次。
Yeah.
是的。
I usually do this.
我通常这样做。
Okay.
好的。
So usually is again, very, very common.
所以“usually”再次非常非常常见。
And something in between maybe 60% of the time, 50% of the time we say regularly.
而介于中间，大约60%的时间，50%的时间，我们说“regularly”。
Well, I think of the word regularly as being very closely related to regular.
嗯，我认为“regularly”这个词与“regular”密切相关。
So basically if I have a schedule, I do the same thing every day.
所以基本上，如果我有日程安排，我每天做同样的事。
I do it regularly.
我定期做。
But sometimes there's a special occasion.
但有时有特殊情况。
For example, I regularly run five kilometers after work when I go to the gym.
例如，我下班后去健身房时，通常跑五公里。
But sometimes when I want to go out with my friends, I don't run.
但有时我想和朋友出去，就不跑了。
So it's not always, but it is pretty regular.
所以不是总是，但相当规律。
Exactly.
正是。
So regularly means you do it very often, but there are some exceptions.
所以“regularly”意味着你经常做，但有一些例外。
Okay.
好的。
Now those are adverbs of frequency, but we have a couple of other phrases that are very
这些是频率副词，但我们还有几个其他短语也非常
similar so we want to take a look at those as well.
类似，所以我们也要看看它们。
Let's go back to the beginning of Stephanie's routine when she said that every day I wake
让我们回到斯蒂芬妮日常生活的开头，她说每天我醒
up.
来。
Okay.
好的。
So every day means 100% of the time every single day.
所以“每天”意味着100%的时间，每一天。
Monday to Sunday.
从周一到周日。
Exactly.
没错。
So obviously you wake up every day.
所以显然你每天都会醒来。
Or I brush my teeth twice every day.
或者我每天刷两次牙。
So that's 100% of the time.
所以那是100%的时间。
Now if we say every second day, what does that mean?
现在如果我们说“每隔一天”，那是什么意思？
That means Monday yes, Tuesday no, Wednesday yes, Thursday no, or any day.
那意味着周一洗，周二不洗，周三洗，周四不洗，或者任何一天。
So basically she says I wash my hair every second day.
所以基本上她说我每隔一天洗一次头发。
That means one day I wash my hair, but the next day I don't.
这意味着有一天我洗头发，但第二天我不洗。
The day after that though, I wash it again.
不过再下一天，我又洗了。
Every second day.
每隔一天。
Okay.
好的。
So you can say every second day and I think you can also say every other day.
所以你可以说“每隔一天”，我想你也可以说“每两天一次”。
Every other day.
每两天一次。
So every other day or every second day.
所以是每隔一天或者每两天一次。
He calls his mother every other day.
他每隔一天给他妈妈打电话。
Very good.
非常好。
Alright.
好的。
And she also said that every now and then I remember to choose my outfit.
她还说，我偶尔会记得挑选我的衣服。
Okay.
好的。
Well, this one's interesting.
嗯，这个挺有意思的。
This is not very frequent.
这个频率不高。
This is basically saying sometimes.
这基本上就是说“有时候”。
Sometimes.
有时候。
So now and then.
所以是“偶尔”。
Every now and then means I sometimes do it, I sometimes don't do it.
“偶尔”的意思是，我有时候做，有时候不做。
Every now and then I really want to eat chocolate so I buy a candy bar.
我偶尔特别想吃巧克力，就会买一块巧克力棒。
Okay.
好的。
So basically you want to eat chocolate twice in a month.
所以基本上你一个月想吃两次巧克力。
Yeah, not very often.
对，不经常。
Not very often.
不经常。
Okay.
好的。
And another one that's very similar is from time to time.
还有一个很相似的表达是“时不时地”。
So Marco said that he doesn't go to the movies very frequently.
所以马可说他不经常去看电影。
So he goes from time to time.
所以他时不时会去。
Right.
对。
So I can say I seldom go to the movies or I can say I like to go to the movies from
所以我可以说我很少去看电影，或者可以说我喜欢时不时去
time to time.
看电影。
That's right.
没错。
Or this girl is describing her appearance.
或者这个女孩在描述她的外表。
She says from time to time I put my hair up.
她说我时不时会把头发盘起来。
So that means most of the time.
这意味着大多数时候。
That means sometimes it's down.
意思是有时候是披着的。
Sometimes it's up.
有时候是盘起来的。
Right.
对。
So as you can see there are many different ways of describing the frequency or how many
所以你看，有很多不同的方式可以描述频率，或者你
times you do certain actions or your routine.
做某些动作或日常事务的次数。
So you can use this with a lot of things when you're describing.
所以你在描述时可以用在很多事情上。
And we encourage you to try some of these new ones because a lot of English learners
我们鼓励你尝试一些新的表达，因为很多英语学习者
use the same time adverbs whenever they speak.
说话时总是用同样的时间副词。
So try and really use some of these and challenge yourself.
所以试着真正用上这些，挑战一下自己。
Exactly.
正是。
All right so that's all we have for language takeaway.
好了，这就是我们语言点学习的全部内容。
Why don't we move on now to Fluency Builder.
我们接下来进入流利度训练吧。
Fluency Builder.
流利度训练。
Okay so using some of these adverbs I could say I can say I regularly make a pot of coffee
好的，所以用这些副词，我可以说，我可以说我早上经常煮一壶咖啡。
in the morning.
在早上。
Okay.
好的。
So a pot of coffee.
所以是一壶咖啡。
You regularly make a pot of coffee.
你经常煮一壶咖啡。
That means you like to drink coffee every day.
这意味着你每天喜欢喝咖啡。
That's right.
没错。
I always need my cup of coffee in the morning.
我早上总是需要一杯咖啡。
So I usually make it first thing.
所以我通常第一件事就是煮咖啡。
So a pot of coffee.
所以是一壶咖啡。
We know what a cup of coffee is.
我们知道一杯咖啡是什么。
But a pot of coffee.
但一壶咖啡。
What is a pot?
壶是什么？
A pot is basically the container that you use when you brew coffee when you make it.
壶基本上是你煮咖啡时用的容器。
So you put the coffee beans in the machine and instead of having a cup underneath you
所以你把咖啡豆放进机器里，而不是在下面放一个杯子，
have a bigger container that's a pot.
你放一个更大的容器，那就是壶。
You can also have a pot of tea.
你也可以有一壶茶。
Exactly.
没错。
It's many cups.
它相当于很多杯。
Usually eight or ten cups.
通常八到十杯。
All right.
好的。
So what is that verb?
那那个动词是什么？
To brew coffee.
泡咖啡。
I think it's a very nice kind of fancy way of saying making coffee.
我觉得这是一种很优雅的说法，相当于“做咖啡”。
Brew a pot of coffee.
煮一壶咖啡。
I'm brewing some coffee.
我正在煮咖啡。
All right.
好的。
So apart from coffee and all of these things, let's take a look at some of the specific
除了咖啡和这些，我们来看看她提到的一些具体
phrases that she used when she was talking about her hair because I think her hair is
短语，关于她的头发，因为我觉得她的头发
very complicated.
很复杂。
It is very complicated.
确实很复杂。
Sometimes she washes her hair.
有时候她洗头发。
Sometimes she doesn't wash her hair.
有时候她不洗头发。
Sometimes she blow dries it straight.
有时候她用吹风机吹直。
Okay, so to blow dry means that you use a blow dryer.
好的，所以“blow dry”意思是你用吹风机。
That's right.
没错。
This is a machine that uses electricity to blow hot air on your hair so that your hair
这是一种用电吹热风到头发上的机器，这样你的头发
will dry quickly.
会干得快。
But you can blow dry your hair in many ways.
但你可以用很多方式吹干头发。
Some people have curly hair and they have special tools for making their hair curly.
有些人有卷发，他们有专门的工具来让头发卷曲。
But she says she blow dries it straight.
但她说她用吹风机吹直。
That means she makes it straight with hot air.
意思是她用热风把头发弄直。
Right.
对。
So I think the way you do this is you take the blow dryer and a brush and you brush while
所以我觉得做法是，你拿着吹风机和梳子，一边吹
you blow dry, right?
一边梳，对吧？
Yep.
嗯。
Awesome.
太棒了。
Making lines.
分线。
See, I know a little bit about this even though I don't have long enough hair for this.
看，我虽然头发不够长，但我也懂一点。
No, I guess.
不，我想是吧。
Well, maybe you are secretly one of those guys who has a routine like this woman.
嗯，也许你私下里就是那种像这个女人一样有固定流程的人。
I don't think I can take this much time in the shower and brushing my hair.
我觉得我花不了这么多时间在淋浴和梳头上。
But moving on, actually, I also know this next phrase, to flat iron your hair.
但继续，实际上，我也知道下一个短语，“用直发夹板拉直头发”。
Okay, so flat iron is a noun and a verb.
好的，所以“flat iron”既是名词也是动词。
So I use a flat iron or I can flat iron my hair.
所以我会用直发夹板，或者我可以拉直头发。
This is a tool that we use that's very, very hot.
这是一种我们用的工具，非常非常热。
Think of an iron.
想象一下熨斗。
It's very, very hot and it basically presses my hair and makes it very, very, very thin
它非常非常热，基本上压住我的头发，让它变得非常非常薄
and flat and straight.
又平又直。
So I think people that have straight hair don't need to really flat iron their hair.
所以我觉得有直发的人不需要真的用直发夹板。
Nah, but if you have very curly hair, then you need it.
不，但如果你有很卷的头发，那你需要它。
So what's the difference?
那有什么区别呢？
Give us the insight here.
给我们讲讲内幕。
Why wouldn't you just blow dry it straight?
为什么你不直接用吹风机吹直？
Why do you need to flat iron it?
为什么需要用直发夹板？
Because a flat iron makes it more flat.
因为直发夹板能让头发更直。
It makes your hair stick together more and it's much, much, much hotter than a blow dryer.
它让头发更贴合，而且比吹风机热得多得多。
So I guess if you use a blow dryer, then you have puffy hair or like the next word that
所以我想如果你用吹风机，头发会蓬松，或者像她描述的
she described, frizzy hair.
下一个词，“毛躁的头发”。
Okay, so the adjective to describe this kind of hair is frizzy.
好的，所以描述这种头发的形容词是“frizzy”。
For example, when it's very rainy, my hair is frizzy.
比如，下雨天的时候，我的头发很毛躁。
That means that it sticks out.
意思是它翘起来。
It's very thick and not straight.
很厚，不直。
It's not curly, but it's messy.
不是卷的，而是乱糟糟的。
It kind of inflates.
有点像膨胀了。
That's right.
没错。
It's like a little balloon.
像个小气球。
But the verb here is to frizz.
但这里的动词是“to frizz”。
So my hair is frizzing.
所以我的头发在毛躁。
And that means that it's getting like this, bigger or inflated.
意思是它变得像这样，更大或膨胀了。
That's right.
没错。
So girls who have this problem have it worse during very humid or rainy days.
所以有这问题的女生在潮湿或下雨天更严重。
Not so bad when it's dry.
干燥的时候没那么糟。
Okay, so I actually have a little bit of frizzy hair.
好的，其实我头发有点毛躁。
That's why I have to use some sort of hair gel or mousse.
所以我得用一些发胶或摩丝。
See, it's not because I'm vain.
看，这不是因为我自恋。
It's just because if I don't use this, I'll come in looking like a lion.
只是如果我不用的，我会看起来像头狮子。
I think I might have to insist that that happens sometime soon.
我想我得坚持让你尽快那样做一次。
We can take a picture and put it on our website, EnglishBot.com.
我们可以拍张照片放到我们网站EnglishBot.com上。
For sure.
当然。
All right, so why don't we go back and listen to the dialogue one last time.
好的，那我们不如回去再听一遍对话吧。
Stephanie, did you just get to school?
Stephanie，你刚到学校吗？
But you were up and about when I left the dorm this morning.
但我早上离开宿舍的时候你已经起床活动了。
That was about an hour and a half ago.
那大约是一个半小时前。
This happens all the time.
这总是发生。
Why do you always take so long to get ready in the mornings?
为什么你早上总是花这么长时间准备？
It's a skill.
这是一种技能。
What can I say?
我能说什么呢？
I don't know why.
我不知道为什么。
I just have a long routine.
我早上的流程很长。
Please explain because it makes no sense to me.
请解释一下，因为我不明白。
How can a girl's routine be so complicated?
一个女生的流程怎么会这么复杂？
You get up, you shower, you get dressed, you brush your teeth, you're out the door.
你起床、洗澡、穿衣服、刷牙，然后出门。
Half an hour tops.
最多半小时。
Jacob, you have the luxury of having a haircut that rarely needs styling.
雅各布，你幸运的是发型几乎不需要打理。
I don't.
我可不行。
I have to set aside about an hour and a half to get ready in the mornings.
我早上得留出一个半小时来准备。
Every day, I wake up and head straight for the shower.
每天，我醒来就直接去洗澡。
Every second day, I wash my hair.
每隔一天，我会洗一次头发。
If it's a hair washing day, I frequently need to wash my hair twice because it gets really
如果是洗头日，我经常需要洗两次，因为头发会变得很
oily.
油。
Then, I usually put in a conditioner and have to rinse that out too.
然后，我通常会涂护发素，还得把它冲洗干净。
Because my hair is so long, I seldom manage to take a shower in under 20 minutes.
因为我的头发很长，我很少能在20分钟内洗完澡。
Afterwards, I often put on a pot of coffee and get dressed while I wait for it to brew.
之后，我经常煮一壶咖啡，在等咖啡煮好的时候穿衣服。
I take a long time to get dressed in the morning.
我早上穿衣服要花很长时间。
Every now and then, I remember to choose my outfit the night before, but usually, I do
偶尔，我会记得前一天晚上选好衣服，但通常，我都是
it in the morning.
早上才选。
In all, getting dressed takes about half an hour, at which time my hair is now semi-dry,
总的来说，穿衣服大约需要半小时，这时我的头发半干了，
so then I have to style my hair.
所以我得打理头发。
From time to time, I'll put my hair up, but oftentimes, I blow-dry it straight.
有时我会把头发扎起来，但经常我会吹直它。
And then, because of the texture of my hair, I regularly have to flat iron it to keep it
然后，因为我的发质，我通常得用直发夹板来防止
from frizzing.
毛躁。
That's another 20 minutes or so.
那又是大约20分钟。
After that, I have my daily makeup routine.
之后，我还有每天的化妆流程。
True.
确实。
I hardly ever see you without your hair done and your makeup on, even when you show up
我几乎从没见过你头发没打理、没化妆的样子，即使你
to class in sweatpants.
穿着运动裤来上课。
Tell me, how long does it take you to choose that outfit in the morning?
告诉我，你早上选那套衣服要花多长时间？
Not funny.
不好笑。
Alright, so actually talking about morning routines, and we've given you so many tools,
好了，实际上说到早上的流程，我们给了你们这么多工具，
I think it would be a great idea if our users came to our site, EnglishPod.com, and posted
我觉得如果我们的用户来我们的网站 EnglishPod.com，并发布
a part of their morning routine, trying to use as many adverbs of frequency as possible.
他们早上流程的一部分，尽量多用频率副词，那会是个好主意。
That's a great suggestion, and to get you all started, I could give you a little bit
这是个好建议，为了让大家开始，我可以简单说说
of my routine.
我的流程。
Alright, let's hear it.
好，说来听听。
Every morning when I wake up, I turn off the alarm, which is very loud, and I take a shower.
每天早上我醒来时，我会关掉很响的闹钟，然后洗澡。
I always brush my teeth, and I usually brew a pot of coffee, although sometimes I don't
我总是刷牙，通常我会煮一壶咖啡，虽然有时我没
have time to brew my coffee, and I wait until I arrive at my office.
时间煮咖啡，就等到办公室再喝。
I seldom choose the clothes I will wear the night before.
我很少在前一晚选好要穿的衣服。
I almost always choose them in the morning, and generally I ride my bike to work, but
我几乎总是在早上选，而且通常我骑自行车上班，但
not always.
不总是这样。
Okay, I think in the winter you seldom ride your bike to work.
好吧，我觉得冬天你很少骑自行车上班。
Every once in a while I ride it.
我偶尔会骑一次。
Alright, see?
好了，看到了吧？
You have a perfect example there of more or less what we expect, but also it would be
你有一个完美的例子，大致符合我们的期望，但也会
interesting to see if you have any other type of routine.
很有趣，看看你们有没有其他类型的流程。
I know some people wake up in the morning, and the first thing they do, they always walk
我知道有些人早上醒来，第一件事总是遛狗，
their dog, for example.
比如。
Oh, that's very nice.
哦，那很好。
Other people are very hungry, so they almost always eat right when they wake up.
其他人很饿，所以他们几乎总是在醒来时就吃东西。
I eat before I brush my teeth.
我在刷牙前吃东西。
Smart, actually.
其实挺聪明的。
Yeah, alright, so we want to hear from you guys.
是啊，好了，所以我们想听听你们的意见。
Come to EnglishPod.com.
来 EnglishPod.com。
We'll see everyone there.
我们会在那里见大家。
Bye.
再见。
Take care.
保重。